Guide to the Lore Parker Papers, 1950-1979 and undated RL.00994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lore Parker papers
1950-1979 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Parker, Lore
RL.00994
12 Linear Feet
Lore Lionel Parker was a copy writer for Doyle Dane Bernbach and other advertising agencies. She was part of the creative team at Bernbach credited with leading the advertising industry's Creative Revolution of the early 1960s. The Lore Parker Papers include proofs, tear sheets and radio and television broadcast scripts for advertising campaigns Parker worked on for Doyle Dane Bernbach, Dowd Redfield & Johnstone, and other advertising agencies. Topics include alcoholic beverages, cosmetics, housewares, snack foods, swimwear, tourism, and women's clothing and undergarments. Major companies or products represented include Alitalia airlines, Barton's Bonbonniere, the British Tourist Authority, Celanese Fibers, Cole of California, General Telephone/GTE, Lees Carpets, and Salada Junket foods.
1251 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Lore Parker Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1926 Born Lore Lionel, Leipzig, Germany
1939 Fled Nazi Germany with family to England
1943-1944 Bilingual secretary, British Broadcasting Corporation
1945 Arrived in U.S.; worked as a secretary at Paris and Peart advertising agency
1952-1956 Copy cub, copywriter, Doyle Dane Bernbach, Inc.
1956-1958 Copywriter, Robert W. Orr agency
1958-1959 Copywriter, Dowd Redfield & Johnstone, Inc.
1959-1982 Doyle Dane Bernbach, Inc. Served in a variety of positions: Copywriter; Vice President and Copy Supervisor; Senior Vice President and Creative Management Supervisor
1982-1985 Vice President and Associate Creative Director, Leber Katz Partners
1985 Retired from Leber Katz
Lore Lionel Parker worked as a copywriter for a number of advertising agencies, and with many of the key creative managers and art directors during what has come to be called the creative revolution in modern advertising: Bill Bernbach, Gene Federico, Bob Gage, Helmut Krone, Phyllis Robinson, Bert Steinhauser, and Bill Taubin. Early in her career, she was known by her maiden name, Lore Lionel, but later by her married name, Lore Parker.
Of her life, Parker writes: I was born in 1926 in Leipzig, Germany, and already as a child wrote poetry--in German, of course. Then came Hitler, the ever-worsening persecution of German Jews, and finally in 1939, my family's hair-breadth escape to England. We arrived penniless, but my brother and I were beneficiaries of Britain's Kindertransport initiative. The British Government had undertaken to accept several thousand Jewish children from Germany and Austria, and place them in the homes of British families who had volunteered to temporarily adopt them. I was adopted by a Girls' High School in the North of England, and lived with the Headmistress, the English mistress, and the Latin mistress in the house they shared. Soon I was writing poems, short stories, and prize-winning essays in English. I had fallen in love with the English language.
During the London Blitz, 1943-1944, I worked at the BBC as a bilingual secretary, so when i finally came to the USA in 1945, I spoke and wrote BBC English. The day after our arrival in New York, I went to an employment agency and asked for a job as a secretary--preferably somewhere where I might eventually be able to write. My English accent didn't hurt. They had two openings: one was with the New York Times, which paid $22.50 a week; the other was with Paris and Peart, an advertising agency--whatever that was. It paid $27.50 a week, and that's how I became a copywriter instead of a journalist.
Collection Overview
The Lore Parker Papers span the years 1950 to 1979 and include proofs, tear sheets and radio and television broadcast scripts for advertising campaigns Parker worked on for Doyle Dane Bernbach (DDB); Dowd, Redfield & Johnstone; and other advertising agencies. Topics include alcoholic beverages, cosmetics, housewares, snack foods, swimwear and bathing suits, tourism, and women's clothing and undergarments. Major companies or products represented include Alitalia airlines, Barton's Bonbonniere, the British Tourist Authority, Celanese Fibers, Cole of California, General Telephone/GTE, Lees Carpets, and Salada Junket foods. Also included are some print advertisements for Ohrbach's, written by DDB Copy chief Phyllis Robinson, which Parker credited as her inspiration to seek employment at DDB.
The collection is arranged into two categories by size: Large Format Items and Small Format Items, and therein alphabetically by company name.
Related Materials:
Materials relating to this collection may be found in the following collections held in the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library: the Advertising Council Records (American Cancer Society); the American Association of Advertising Agencies Records (Ocean Spray); the Bates Worldwide, Inc. Records (Alitalia, GTE); the Ben Rosen Papers (Barton Bonbonniere); the Brouillard Communications, Inc., Records (GTE); the D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles Archives (Stroh's beer); the Garrett Orr Papers (Chemstrand, Ocean Spray, Salada Tea); the Gene Federico Papers (American Cancer Society, GTE, Woman's Day); the J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files (Salada Tea); the J. Walter Thompson Company Chicago Office Records (Salada Tea); the J. Walter Thompson Company Corporation Vertical Files (Ocean Spray); the J. Walter Thompson Company Domestic Advertising Collection (American Cancer Society); the J. Walter Thompson Company Review Board Records (Wolfschmidt); and the Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements (Bayer).
Women's clothing; Scripts (documents); Tear sheets; Advertising -- Clothing and dress; Advertising -- Cosmetics; Advertising -- Alcoholic beverages -- United States; Underwear; Foundation garments; Clothing and dress; Bathing suits; Advertising -- Tourism; Household appliances; Lingerie; Radio advertising; Snack foods; Television advertising; Proofs (printed matter); Celanese Corporation; British Tourist Authority; Dowd, Redfield, & Johnstone, Inc. (Firm); Cole of California (Firm) [not LC]; General Telephone & Electronics Corporation; Doyle Dane Bernbach Inc.; Lees Carpets (Firm) [not LC]; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Parker, Lore; Salada Tea Company (Firm) [not LC]; Ohrbach's Department Store. [not LC]; Parker, Lore; Barton's Bonbonniere (Firm) [not LC]; Alitalia (Airline)
- Large Format Items, 1950-1979 and undated, 6 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes proofs and tearsheets, along with some radio and television spot scripts. Smaller items have been removed to the Small Format Items series. Where an entire folder has been removed, the company name is indicated in brackets; otherwise, a note in parentheses indicates where partial folders have been removed. Arranged alphabetically by company name.
  - Alitalia, 1958-1959 and undated (See also Small Format Items, Box 7), 3 folders (Box 1)
  - American Cancer Society, undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Amstel, undated (Box 1)
  - [Ban de Soleil: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 1)
  - Barton's Bonbonniere, 1954-1955 and undated (see also Small Format Items, Box 7), 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes advertisements for Kosher chocolate, aimed at Jewish holidays.
  - Bayer, 1977 and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - British Tourist Authority, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Celanese, 1975-1976 (See also Small Format Items, Box 7) (Box 2)
  - Chemstrand, 1955-1965 (See also Small Format Items, Box 7), 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Clairol, 1962-1970 (See also Small Format Items, Box 7) (Box 2)
  - Cole of California, 1955-1961 (See also Small Format Items, Box 7), 2 folders (Box 2)
  - [Croton: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 2)
  - Ecko Housewares, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Einiger, 1953-1954 and undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - European Travel Commission, 1959 and undated (See also Small Format Items, Box 7) (Box 2)
  - [Fairmont: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 2)
  - 5-Day Deodorant, 1950-1960 (See also Small Format Items, Box 7), 2 folders (Box 3)
  - [Flexalum: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 3)
  - French Government Tourist Office, 1962 (Box 3)
  - General Mills, 1964-1966 and undated (Box 3)
  - Gillette, 1959 and undated (Box 3)
  - Golden Glow Margarine, 1966-1967 (See also Small Format Items, Box 7) (Box 3)
  - GTE, 1975 and undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Handmacher, 1955 and undated (Box 3)
  - Hess Brothers, 1954-1955 and undated (Box 3)
  - Hillman, 1958 and undated (Box 3)
  - [Hotel Corporation of America: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 3)
  - Incres Agency, Inc., 1959 (Box 4)
  - [Indulge: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 4)
  - International Silver, 1962-1963 and undated (Box 4)
  - [Italian State Tourist Office: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 4)
  - [Jamaica Tourist: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 4)
  - [Jana: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 4)
  - [Lambretta: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 4)
  - [Lanvin: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 4)
  - Lawry's, 1960 and undated, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Lees Carpets, 1970-1973 and undated (See also Small Format Items, Box 7) (Box 4)
  - [Lovable: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 4)
  - [Max Factor: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 4)
  - McCall's Patterns, 1955-1956 and undated (Box 5)
  - Mona Lisa Foundations, Inc., 1953 and undated (See also Small Format Items, Box 7) (Box 5)
  - Necchi, 1953-1954 and undated (Box 5)
  - Nitey-Nite, 1955 and undated (Box 5)
  - [Northwest Airlines: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 5)
  - Ocean Spray Cranberries, Inc., 1966-1967, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Ohrbach's, 1952-1960, 2 folders (Box 5)
    Copy written by Phyllis Robinson. The early executions of these advertisements inspired Parker to seek employment at Doyle Dane Bernbach.
  - [Ore-Ida Food, Inc. (Tater Tots): see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 5)
  - Pristeen, 1969-1970 (See also Small Format Items, Box 7), 2 folders (Box 5)
  - [Quaker Oatmeal: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 5)
  - [Railway Express Agency: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 5)
  - [Regal: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 5)
  - Revlon, 1958 and undated (Box 5)
  - Salada, 1960 and undated (See also Small Format Items, Box 7), 2 folders (Box 6)
  - [Standard Brands, Inc.: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 6)
  - Stroh's, 1950 and undated, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Suzy Perette, undated (Box 6)
  - [Tangee: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 6)
  - Warner's, 1962-1963, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - [Wear-Right: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 6)
  - Wolfschmidt's, 1958 and undated, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Woman's Day, 1953-1956 (See also Small Format Items, Box 7), 2 folders (Box 6)
  - [Woodbury: see Small Format Items, Box 7] (Box 6)
  - Yardley, 1961 and undated (Box 6)
- Small Format Items, 1950-1979 and undated, 1 box
  Arranged alphabetically by company name.
  - Alitalia, 1958-1959 and undated, 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes articles on the advertising campaign.
  - Ban de Soleil, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Celanese, 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Chemstrand, 1955-1965 (Box 7)
  - Clairol, 1962-1970 (Box 7)
  - Cole of California, 1955-1961, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Croton, 1953 and undated (Box 7)
  - European Travel Commission, 1959 and undated (Box 7)
  - Fairmont, 1956 and undated (Box 7)
  - 5 Day Deodorant, 1950-1960 (Box 7)
  - Flexalum, undated (Box 7)
  - Golden Glow Margarine, 1966-1967 (Box 7)
  - Hotel Corporation of America, undated (Box 7)
  - Indulge, undated (Box 7)
  - Italian State Tourist Office, 1958 and undated (Box 7)
  - Jamaica Tourist, undated (Box 7)
  - Jana, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Lambretta, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Lanvin, 1950 and undated (Box 7)
  - Lees Carpets, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 7)
  - Lovable, 1958 and undated (Box 7)
  - Max Factor, 1953-1954 and undated (Box 7)
  - Mona Lisa Foundations, 1953 and undated (Box 7)
  - Northwest Airlines, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Ore Ida Foods (Tater Tots), 1977 (Box 7)
  - Pristeen, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Quaker Oats, undated (Box 7)
  - Railway Express Agency (Air Express), undated (Box 7)
  - Regal, 1955 (Box 7)
  - Salada, 1960 and undated (Box 7)
  - Standard Brands (Blue Bonnet), 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Tangee, undated (Box 7)
  - Wear-Right, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Woman's Day, 1953-1956 (Box 7)
  - Woodbury, 1957 and undated (Box 7)